nick@cullaloe.com http://cullaloe.com/

Synopsis

Educator, physicist and software engineer. Broad and extensive experience of internet technologies and data-driven web solutions. International track record in Education, IT, Project Management, Simulation and Training. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills at all levels.

EDUCATION

Edinburgh University, Moray House School of Education

• PGCE (Secondary: Physics and Mathematics), July 2004

The Open University, Milton Keynes

• B.Sc. (Hons), November 2002

QUALIFICATIONS

The General Teaching Council for Scotland

- Full Registration (Mathematics), April 2006
- Full Registration (Physics with Science), July 2005

The Science Council

• Chartered Scientist (CSci), July 2004

The Institute of Physics

- Member (MInstP), July 2003
- Chartered Physicist (CPhys), July 2003

The Microsoft Corporation

- MCSD Charter Member, 1999
- Microsoft Certified Solution Developer, June 2001

The Royal Aeronautical Society

• Corporate Member (MRAeS), August 1999



Solution Developer

Professional EXPERIENCE

cullaloe.net trading as Al Muhandis, Fife

April 2003 to date

Sole trader business providing consultancy and technical services.

- Designed and implemented community website for Physics Teachers in Scotland at http://sptr.net using WordPress, PHP, mySQL, Javascript, JSON, WP Plugins including customisation of these
- Implemented and rolled out Project Management System using Ruby on Rails, Redmine, mySQL on Centos 6.4
- Hosting several community and business websites using WordPress, Joomla! Drupal at http://cullaloe.net
- Set up community sites using phpBB, mySQL (e.g. http://sptr.net/forum)
- Established educational websites using Moodle, Joomla!, WordPress, MediaWiki, ELGG and other suites
- Unix server administration on shared hosting and VPS including configuration, upgrade, extension and scripting of tools

Edinburgh University, Moray House

August 2012 to August 2014

Teaching Fellow seconded to lead the PGDE Secondary Physics programme. Also teaching on Secondary PGDE General Science and science strand leader for Primary PGDE/BEd Science.

Fife Regional Council, Education Service

August 2004 to July 2012

Principal Teacher, Physics (Glenwood HS)

Teacher of Physics & Mathematics (Kirkcaldy HS)

Teacher of Physics & Mathematics (Probationer, Buckhaven HS)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Cullaloe Project Resource Ltd

February 1997 – July 2003

Fixed rate, fixed price and cost-plus contracts for clients, including:

• The Scottish Centre for Infection & Environmental Health

Designed and built the medical reporting system ECOSS using SQL Server 7.0, NT4/IIS, .asp, XML, XSLT, VSS, UNIX

Designed and built the Quick Response (GP Medical) Surveillance System QRSS using SQL Server 7.0, NT4/IIS, MAPI (Exchange)

Delivered training and full documentation for users and support staff

• Purves Plant Hire

Design specification for plant tracking/scheduling database application using NT4. Access, Windows 2000

• West Lothian Council

Conversion of Pagemaker 6.5 forms to dynamic Adobe pdf forms

• Scarlet Training

Contract trainer, delivering courses on HTML 4 (Intro and mastering), Java programming, Dreamweaver 4/UltraDev, Adobe PDF programming, Microsoft Mastering VB6 series (Fundamentals, Development, Enterprise, Web App Development), MOC833 SQL Server 7

• LearningIT

Contract trainer, delivering courses in advanced HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java programming, Java for C programmers

• Aspentech

Design analysis & report on the Heysham 2 Process Plant Simulation upgrade

• Greater Glasgow & Clyde Valley Tourist Board

Design and implementation of the visitor information and accommodation booking system website using SQL Server, NT4/IIS, ASP, XLS/XSLT, Javascript, dynamic HTML

• Deutsche Bank

Design and development of Private Clients Investment management system using Access/VB6/NT/Win2K

• Bull

Design and development of Kwik-Fit Insurance call centre suite using Graham Technologies GT-X system, VB6/NT

• ICL

Systems update (Millennium Bug) for tools and utilities using VB4/SQL

• Anglian Water

Support and programming for systems roll-out using VB4/Windows98/2K/NT

GEC Marconi Simulation and Training July 1991 – February 1997

 $Senior\ Software\ Engineer$

- GUI application development for auto-initialisation code generation in C
- Designed and coded a fault injection package, real-time process plant simulation models and a developer's toolkit for real-time parameter display
- Using: Microsoft VB 4.0, Access SQL, C/C++, VSS, NT3.51

Data Control Manager

• Software Configuration and Engineering Control, Shajiao , C Power Station

Bid/Project Manager - Military Operations

- Connah's Quay Power Station simulator
- AS 90 and Warrior OPV military vehicle simulator
- Sea King HAR Mk3A Radar Crew Trainer
- CATT Feasibility Study, MECCA/MARCAS IT system feasibility study
- Bids for AFV Turret (Kuwait) and Sea Harrier FRS.2 Maintenance Trainers

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

IMACS (UK) Limited, Worthing

February 1990 - May 1991

Commercial Manager

• Business Planning and development. Contract negotiation. Facility management including bespoke MIS/IT Systems and Practices.

Aviation Resources Limited, West Sussex March 1989 – February 1990 Technical Director

• Lear Jet procedures trainer (Aylesbury). Technical staff recruitment and deployment (Broken Arrow)

British Aerospace Simulation Ltd, Weybridge Chief Project Manager – Civil Aircraft Projects

- Jetstream J31 and BAe 146 Phase II Full Flight Simulators (Washington)
- Advanced Turboprop (ATP) Phase II FFS (Woodford)
- BAe146 Cockpit Procedures Trainer (Hatfield)
- Business Development within BAe and European Civil Markets
- Technical Consultancy for Reflectone, Inc., during acquisition by BAe (Tampa)

IMACS (UK) Limited, Worthing Rediffusion Simulation Ltd, Crawley February 1986 – September 1988 August 1981 – February 1986

Project Manager

- Visual Display Systems in Concorde, B737, B747, A320, BAe Jetstream Full Flight Simulators for BA, Lufthansa, KLM, SIA and British Aerospace
- Boeing B757/767 Maintenance Trainer update (Seattle)
- TWA B767 Flight Test Update (Kansas City)
- JAL B767 FFS installation and JCAB approval (FAA Phase II) in Tokyo

Systems Design Engineer

- EICAS systems expert for the Boeing B757/767 Maintenance Trainer update
- Designed and modelled the Autobrakes & Secondary Flight Controls Systems for a DC10-30 Cockpit Procedures Trainer.
- Designed and implemented real-time models of aircraft systems in B737, DC-10, L-1011 and B1-B Full Flight Simulators.
- Languages: FORTRAN77, Assembler, JCL & GENESIS.
- Operating Systems: GOULD-SEL32 RTM & MPX.

Freelance Sales, London

Life Assurance, Telecom and Medical October 1980 – August 1981 Army (Royal Electrical and Mechanical Engineers) April 1976 – October 1980 Avionics Technician, Class II

Westland Scout, Gazelle, Lynx and DeHavilland Beaver

Wilbury Hotel, Letchworth

Bar / cellarman October 1975 – April 1976

C. Hartley and Sons (China & Glass) Ltd, Letchworth

Driver/storeman May 1975 - October 1975

Jones Cranes Limited, Letchworth

Sales Liaison Officer

May 1974 - May 1975

END